<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><add><doc><field name="collectionId">tamwag</field><field name="uri">http://localhost/findingaids/html/tamwag/alumnifed</field><field name="id">tamwag_alumnifed</field><field name="title">Records of the Alumni Federation of New York University, Inc. RG 40.7</field><field name="scopecontentURI">ref366</field><field name="description.scopecontent">This collection contains 12.1 linear feet of materials in 10 boxes. The materials date from 1919 to 1995, but the bulk of the collection dates from 1919 to 1940. Records include meeting minutes, correspondence, budgets, and materials related to special events and alumni relations. The bulk of the materials comes from the office of the Alumni Federation Secretary Benjamin A. Ross.</field><field name="bioghistURI">ref365</field><field name="bioghist">The Alumni Federation of New York University was incorporated in 1921. Officially, the Alumni Federation united what had previously been separate alumni groups from the different schools and colleges of the University. Prior to the formation of the Alumni Federation, the General Alumni Association existed but with little or no mandate to coordinate the administration of alumni activities. The Alumni Federation Board of Governors was organized with 21 members from the different alumni groups, with the largest schools contributing the most representatives. By 1940, amendments to the Alumni Federation constitution replaced the Board of Governors with a Board of Directors and increased its membership. Representatives to the Board were chosen based on a “Class” system, where larger associations, in Class A, contributed more representatives and had more power on the Board than Classes B and C.</field><field name="bioghist">The Alumni Federation oversaw the involvement of alumni within the University, hosted events and activities, and administered the Alumni Fund. Awards and honors like the Great Teachers Award were given out by the Alumni Federation to individuals for their achievements and contributions to the University. The Alumni Federation also published newsletters and magazines like the 
                .</field><field name="bioghist">In the 1980s, the relationship of the Alumni Federation and the University became strained. The University desired to have more control over the Federation’s fundraising efforts, especially in engaging with younger alumni and connecting with alumni outside of the New York metropolitan area. The University requested, after a special review, that the Alumni Federation staff director report to the President of the University in addition to the Federation's Board of Directors. This request was made to justify the $2.7 million in annual assistance the University gave the Federation. In January of 1985, the Alumni Federation decided to become an operationally independent organization and by that autumn, it was no longer recognized and its activities no longer endorsed by the University.</field><field name="bioghist">By 1995, the Alumni Federation had been significantly restructured and was mainly administered by alumni from the 1940s, 1950s, and 1960s. The last Board of Directors minutes in the collection date from June 22, 1995.</field><field name="containerURI">dscd3e330</field><field name="description.dsc.glob">Series I: Administrative MaterialsNYU Alumni Association Annual ReportNYU Alumni Federation Rules of Procedure, Articles of FederationNYU Alumni Federation Certification of IncorporationNYU Alumni Federation Certification of Incorporation AmendmentsNYU Alumni Federation Increase in Number of Directors and Amended Incorporation, Bylaws, and RulesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors, Minutes &amp; ReportsNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors, Minutes &amp; ReportsNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors, Minutes &amp; ReportsNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors, Minutes &amp; ReportsNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors Special Accounting CommitteeNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors and Members, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors and Members, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors and Members, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors and Members, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors and Members, MinutesNYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors (1 of 2)NYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors (2 of 2)Alumni Federation Past Presidents 1921-1985NYU Alumni Federation Board of Directors 1984-1985NYU Alumni Federation Directors - Class A 1984-1985NYU Alumni Federation Directors - Class B 1984-1985NYU Alumni Federation Directors - Class C 1984-1985NYU Alumni Federation Directors - Class D 1984-1985NYU Alumni Federation Committees 1984-1985Series II: Alumni Federation ActivitiesMedallion Alumni Society 1984-1985Meritorious Service Awards Committee 1984-1985Presidents of the Alumni Association 1984-1985Recipients of Director Emeritus Award 1966-1984NYU Alumni Associations and Clubs, Officers and Directors 1984-1985Alumni Federation "Transition"Alumni Federation BudgetNYU Alumni Federation Officers and Directories 1990-1992Alumni Directory SurveyNYU Alumni FundNYU Alumni FundNYU Alumni FundAlumni ScholarshipsAlumni Service CorporationAlumni Service Corporation Incorporation DocumentsAlumnus Magazine - American Alumni Council "Continued Education" SeriesAlumnus MagazineAlumnus Magazine AdvertisersThe American University Club of New York, Inc.Auditors' ReportsThe Cayuga Press CorrespondenceThe Cayuga PressThe Cayuga PressGraduate Group, Inc. (1 of 2)Graduate Group, Inc. (2 of 2)Graduate Group, Inc.Graduate Group, Inc.Graduate Group, Inc."Grid-graph" MaterialsLoomis, Suffern, and Fernald AccountantsMedallic Art CompanyMotion Picture CommitteeNew York UniversityPost MasterSociety for the Libraries of New York UniversityAlumni Day MailingsCarnival Dinner, NYU Alumni Federation, October 16th, 1926NYU Centennial All-Alumni Dinner, March 1st, 1932Centennial CommencementChancellor Brown Testimonial Dinner, May 3rd, 1933Chancellor Chase Welcome Dinner, October 31st, 1933L. Jay Oliva Inaugural Reception, Novembr 19, 1991NYU Alumni Authors and their PublicationsAlumni Associations' Awards 1951-1982Honorary Degrees 1850-1984Alumni Meritorious Service Award Recipients through 1988Gallatin Associates Medal 1957-1988New York University Medal 1956-1981Presidential Citation 1957-1982Alumni Fund 1927-1928Commencement Attenance Totals 1933-1980NYU Club Officers 1956-1982Alumni Trophy Selectors 1959-1968Bobst Awards in Arts and Letters 1982 and 1983Great Teachers Award Program Administrative FilesGreat Teachers by Year/School from 1959 to 1991Great Teachers 1978Great Teachers 1979Great Teachers 1980Great Teachers 1981Great Teachers 1982Great Teachers 1983Great Teachers 1984Great Teachers 1985Great Teachers 1986Great Teachers 1987Series III: Affiliated Alumni Groups &amp; ActivitiesNYU Men in Advertising ClubNYU Men in Finance ClubGraduate School of Business Administration Alumni AssociationInstitute of Business (1 of 2)Institute of Business (2 of 2)Institute of BusinessProceedings of the First and Second Annual Meetings of the Institute of BusinessProceedings for the Third Annual Meeting of the Institute of BusinessAddresses from the Institute of Business Meeting on DistributionInstitute of Business, Problems and Trends in Distribution (1 of 3)Institute of Business, Problems and Trends in Distribution (2 of 3)Institute of Business, Problems and Trends in Distribution (3 of 3)3rd Annual Federation Finance Forum - Oct. 31, 1987Colleges of Arts and Engineering Alumni AssociationArts and Engineering Alumni AssociationLoose papers - Arts and EngineeringArts and Engineering1890 Arts and Engineering1893 Arts and Engineering1894 Arts and Engineering1900 Arts and Engineering1904 Arts and Engineering1905 Arts and Engineering1906-1915 Arts and Engineering1917-1928 Arts and Engineering1929 Arts and Engineering1930 Arts and Engineering1931 Arts and Engineering1932 Arts and EngineeringArts and Engineering Alumni AssociationArts and Engineering Midwinter Reunion 1934Arts and Engineering Spring Alumni Day - June 2, 1934Arts and Engineering Spring Alumni Day - June 8, 1935Arts and Engineering Dinner - Feb. 11, 1935Arts and Engineering Alumni AssociationArts and Engineering Spring Alumni Day - May 16, 1936Arts and Engineering Dinner - Feb. 20, 1936Arts and Engineering ActivitiesArts and Engineering Dinner - Feb. 24, 1938Arts and Engineering Dinner - March 2, 1939 (1 of 2)Arts and Engineering Dinner - March 2, 1939 (2 of 2)Engineers ClubSchool of Commerce Alumni AssociationSchool of Commerce Classes '02, '03, '05 through '12School of Commerce Classes '14, '15, '16School of Commerce Classes '17School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance Alumni Association Dinners and MinutesSchool of Commerce Alumni AssociationSchool of Commerce Classes '18, '19, '20School of Commerce Class of '21School of Commerce Class of '22, '23School of Commerce Class of '24School of Commerce Class of '25School of Commerce Class of '27 Dinner and Silver JubileeSchool of Commerce Class of '28School of Commerce Class of '291929 School of Commerce Alumni Association Dinner1930 School of Commerce "Senior Hop"School of Commerce Alumni Dinner May 2, 1935School of Commerce Reunion Dinner May 7, 1936School of Commerce Class of '13School of Commerce Alumni ActivitiesSchool of Commerce ActivitiesDental School Class of '05Dental School Classes of '14 to '19Dental School Alumni ActivitiesDental School Clinic and Dinner 1929Dental School Alumni Days 1929Dental School Clinic and Dinner 1930Dental School 1931 MeetingDental School Dinner and Alumni Day 1931Dental School Alumni Dinner 1933Dental School Alumni Days 1933Dental School Post-Graduate CoursesDental College Alumni AssociationDental College Alumni AssociationDental College Alumni AssociationDental College Alumni AssociationDental College Alumni AssociationSchool of Education Alumni AssociationSchool of Education Alumni AssociationSchool of Education Alumni AssociationSchool of Education Alumni AssociationSchool of Education Alumni AssociationSchool of Education Alumni AssociationDoctors of Philosophy ClubDoctors of Philosophy, Graduate School Alumni AssociationDoctors of Philosophy Club, Graduate School Alumni AssociationLaw School Class of 1893Law School Class of 1894Law School Class of 1897Law School Class of 1898Law School Class of 1899Law School Class of 1900Law School Class of 1902Law School Class of 1905Law School Class of 1909Law School Class of 1910Law School Class of 1914 to 1917Law School Class of 1918Law School Class of 1919Law School Class of 1920Law School Class of 1921Law School Class of 1922Law School Class of 1923Law School Class of 1924Law School Class of 1925Law School Class of 1926Law School Alumni Association Annual Dinners 1912-1927Law School Alumni Association Dinners 1928-1929Law School Alumni Association Dinners 1931-1936Law School Conference on Debt Relief LawsLaw Dinner, March 16, 1937, Waldorf Astoria Hotel (1 of 2)Law Dinner, March 16, 1937, Waldorf Astoria Hotel (2 of 2)Law Dinner, March 9, 1938Law School ActivitiesLaw School ActivitiesLaw Dinner, May 10, 1939 (postponed)Law Alumni Arbitration Luncheon, February 23, 1938Medical College Alumni AssociationMedical College Association ActivitiesMedical College Association ActivitiesMedical Alumni NoticesMedical College Association ActivitiesMedical College Association ActivitiesSchool of Retailing Alumni ActivitiesRetailing Class of 1926Veterinary College Alumni AssociationVeterinary College Alumni ActivitiesVeterinary Dinner-Dance, May 7, 1931Washington Square College Class of 1919Washington Square College Class of 1920Washington Square College Class of 1921Washington Square College Class of 1922, 1923, and 1924Washington Square College Class of 1926, 1927, and 1928Washington Square College Alumni ActivitiesWashington Square College Alumni ActivitiesNYU Letter ClubNYU Letter ClubNYU Letter Club ActivitiesNYU Letter Club Basketball DinnerCarnegie Tech Football GameCarnegie Tech Football Game (1 of 2)Carnegie Tech Football Game (2 of 2)Alumni Activities - FootballFootball Coaches Dinner NYAC, April 19, 1934Football DinnerNYU Letter Club ActivitiesNebraska - NYU Football Game TripAlumni Activities - Bermuda CruiseNew York University Centennial FundChancellor's Alumni Meeting, May 22, 1934New York University Community RelationsChancellor's Committee on Alumni OpinionNew York Conference of UniversitiesPurchase of Original NYU DiplomaOhio State - NYU Football Game and Trip, October 3, 1936NYU Tennis Club 1900-1927Newman ClubAlumni Occupational ListsLawrence House Student Union, YMCABureau of EmploymentNew York Alumni Club of Delta Sigma PiNew York Alumni Club of Delta Sigma PiAlpha Kappa Psi FraternityPhi Gamma Delta StationeryPhi Gamma Delta - GeneralPhi Gamma Delta - GeneralPhi Gamma Delta DirectoriesPhi Gamma Delta Association Records and CorrespondencePhi Gamma Delta AuditGeorge Kastener Correspondence and Addresses/Paper Clippings (Secretary)Charles D. Haughey Correspondence (Treasurer)"Hall of Fame Fiji": Nu Epsilon Chapter of Phi Gamma DeltaPhi Gamma Delta 50th AnniversaryPhi Gamma Delta ActivitiesPhi Gamma Delta National Office (1 of 2)Phi Gamma Delta National Office (2 of 2)Phi Gamma Delta Chapter MaterialsPhi Gamma Delta General Correspondence2274 Loring Place, Morrison and Lynn Attorneys2274 Loring Place, Fire InsurancePhi Gamma Delta Alumni Bartley to LoughranPhi Gamma Delta Alumni Mautel to YoungOversized Materials and EphemeraSeries IV: CorrespondenceAlexander F. Makay &amp; CompanyBarr, Jean B., Supervisor of PrintingBadger, Phillip O., Professor of MarketingBriesen, Fritz, Law '97Broderick, Joseph, Commerce '06Brown, Samuel A., Medicine '94Chase, Harry Woodburn, ChancellorClyne, James F., Editor "New York University Alumnus" (1 of 3)Clyne, James F., Editor "New York University Alumnus" (2 of 3)Clyne, James F., Editor "New York University Alumnus" (3 of 3)Draper, Arthur S., Engineering '05Draper, Arthur S., Engineering '05Fernald, Henry B., Arts '01GeneralGarvin, Edwin L., Arts '97 and Law '99Hendershot, W. Raymond, Commerce '20Irwin, John V., Arts '94 and Law '99Irwin, John V., Arts '94 and Law '99Jones, Theodore F., Director of Heights Library and Professor of HistoryKent, Fred I., University CouncilKimball, Leroy E., ComptrollerKingsley, William M., Arts '84Larsen, George, Arts '06Makay, Alexander F., Commerce '09 (1 of 2)Makay, Alexander F., Commerce '09 (2 of 2)Makay, Alexander F., Commerce '09Onderdonk, Charles D., Office ManagerPatterson, William M., Law '93 (1 of 2)Patterson, William M., Law '93 (2 of 2)Patterson, William M., Law '93 (1 of 2)Patterson, William M., Law '93 (2 of 2)Patterson, William M., Law '93 (1 of 2)Patterson, William M., Law '93 (2 of 2)Roberts, VincentRoberts, VincentRoss, Benjamin A., Alumni Federation Secretary (1 of 2)Ross, Banjamin A., Alumni Federation Secretary (2 of 2)Saunders, Richard P.Sommer, Frank H., Dean of Law SchoolTompkins, Leslie J., Law '92Voorhis, Harold O., NYU Secretary (1 of 2)Voorhis, Harold O., NYU Secretary (2 of 2)Voorhis, Harold O., NYU SecretaryWashburn, Earle L., NYU Auditor</field></doc></add>